Guide to the Vassar College Scrapbooks, 1860-1978
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Scrapbooks
1860-1978
Vassar College
20 cubic feet (33 volumes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings and programs relating to Vassar College events and issues.
Administrative History
Vassar College was founded in 1861 and opened its doors in 1865.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings and programs relating to Vassar College events and issues. It is unclear what person(s) or office(s) compiled the scrapbooks, however Vassar's Office of Public Relations (now Communications) likely played a significant role in the production of the news stories the scrapbooks contain.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women--Education
Document Types:
Scrapbooks
VCL Categories:
Vassar College Events and Issues
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, September 2011. Updated by Mark Seidl, July 2022.
Other Formats
Also available on microfilm.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series. The first series consists of the scrapbooks containing primarily newspaper clippings. The second series consists of supplements to the scrapbooks (volumes 1-22 only). The third series consists of one scrapbook containing Vassar event programs.
Series List
- Series I. Scrapbooks
  - 12 January 1860-17 June 1892 (Volume 1)
  - 9 October 1892-17 May 1904 (Volume 2)
  - 21 May 1904-14 March 1911 (Volume 3)
  - 9 March 1911-1 December 1914 (Volume 4)
  - 2 December 1914-27 February 1917 (Volume 5)
  - 1 March 1917-28 April 1921 (Volume 6)
  - 28 April 1921-28 July 1923 (Volume 7)
  - 17 June 1923-30 September 1925 (Volume 8)
  - 1 October 1925-3 April 1928 (Volume 9)
  - 4 April 1928-24 January 1933 (Volume 10)
  - 22 January 1933-13 June 1937 (Volume 11)
  - 7 June 1937-21 December 1941 (Volume 12)
  - 3 January 1942-15 March 1946 (Volume 13)
  - 16 March 1946-31 December 1948 (Volume 14)
  - 7 January 1949-29 May 1952 (Volume 15)
  - 1 June 1954-31 October 1956 (Volume 16)
  - 4 November 1956-27 June 1960 (Volume 17)
  - 7 July 1960-1 December 1961 (Volume 18)
  - 5 January 1962-31 March 1970 (Volume 19)
  - 13 July 1966-17 March 1970 (Volume 20)
  - 20 March 1970-16 December 1973 (Volume 21)
  - 17 December 1973-3 April 1977 (Volume 22)
  - 6 April 1977-31 October 1978 (Volume 23)
- Series II. Supplements
  - 1860-1899, [for volumes 1-2] (Supplement 1)
  - 1900-1919, [for volumes 3-5] (Supplement 2)
  - 1920-1939, [for volumes 6-11] (Supplement 3)
  - 1940-1942, [for volume 12] (Supplement 4)
  - 1943-1951, [for volume 13] (Supplement 5)
  - 1952-1974, [for volumes 14-22] (Supplement 6)
- Series III. Programs
  - 1883-1922 (Volume 1)